George Gaylord Simpson Papers 1918-1984 Mss.Ms.Coll.31
American Philosophical Society
- George Gaylord Simpson Papers
  - Series I. Correspondence, 1925-1984; 36 linear feet (Box 1-73)
    - Musterschmidt (journal), 1954, 1960 (Box 43)
    - Myers, Betty June, 1965, 1967 (Box 43)
    - Myers, George S., 1940, 1951, 1968 (Box 43)
    - Myers, Robin, 1961 (Box 43)
      Collier Press
    - Myers, Susan, 1963 (Box 43)
    - Myllymaki, Arvo, 1981 (Box 43)
    - Nace, Raymond L., 1936-38 (Box 43)
    - Nacional de Geografia, 1931 (Box 43)
    - Nagao, Takumi, 1937 (Box 43)
    - Nagel, Ernest, 1960 (Box 43)
    - Nagele, J., 1966 (Box 43)
    - Nagera, Juan Jose, 1932-33 (Box 43)
    - Nagy, Bartholomew, 1978 (Box 43)
    - Nagy, Lois Anne, 1969, 77 (Box 43)
    - Nagy, Peter, 1969 (Box 43)
    - Naiburg, L., 1977 (Box 43)
    - Napier, John, 1963 (Box 43)
    - Nash, Leanne T., 1975-76 (Box 43)
      Arizona State University
    - Nash, Louise, 1928 (Box 43)
    - Nation (magazine), 1958, 65 (Box 43)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1941-1983; 15 folders (Box 43-44)
      Biographical and personal data; Evolution; Genetics; Honors -- Elliot Medal; National Academy of Sciences; Paleontology; Publication
      - Attacks on D.E.U. Condon, 1948 (Box 43)
      - Daniel Giraud Elliot Medal, 1946, 49, 53, 56, 65-66, 68-70 (Box 43)
      - Effects of Sonic Boom, 1968 (Box 43)
      - Executive offices, 1941-56, 64, 68, 71, 73, 79-83 (Box 43)
      - Genetics, Paleontology, and Evolution volume, 1948-49 (Box 44)
      - Marsh Fund, 1941-43, 47-50 (Box 44)
      - Mary Clark Thompson Fund and Award, 1941, 43, 48, 54-55 (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous, 1941-52, 57, 63, 65-66, 71 (Box 44)
      - Resumes of Candidates for nomination, ca. 1977 (Box 44)
      - Section of Geology, 1942-52, 58-60, 71, 77-78 (Box 44)
    - National Association of Biological Teachers, 1965 (Box 44)
    - National Audubon Society, 1973 (Box 44)
      Antartica
    - National Book Award, 1954 (Box 44)
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ, 1967 (Box 44)
    - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1937 (Box 44)
    - National Geographic Society, 1962-63, 65, 68-71, 78, 82 (Box 44)
      Webb, Sawney David
    - National Geological Survey of China, 1947 (Box 44)
    - National Institute of Mental Health, 1971-72 (Box 44)
    - National Medal of Science, 1965-66 (Box 44)
    - National Museum of Canada, 1970 (Box 44)
    - National Museum of Victoria, 1968-69 (Box 44)
    - National Research Council (Box 44-46)
      - Committee on the Common Problems of Genetics, Paleontology, and Evolution, 1942-1949; 10 folders (Box 44-45)
        Business; Evolution; Genetics; National Research Council -- Committee activities; Paleontology; Publication
        - Correspondence #1, 1942-1944 (Box 44)
        - Correspondence #2, 1945 (Box 44)
        - Correspondence #3, 1946 (Box 44)
        - Correspondence #4, 1947 (Box 45)
        - Correspondence #5, 1948-1949 (Box 45)
        - Bulletins, 1942-1949 (Box 45)
        - Expenses, 1946-1947 (Box 45)
      - Committee on the Application of Bioliological Methods and Data to Geological Problems, 1946-47 (Box 45)
      - Committee on Systematic Biology, 1956-57 (Box 45)
      - Concepts in Biology Conference, 1955-58; 2 folders (Box 45)
        Includes: report, transcript
      - Fellowship in the Biological Sciences, 1926-29, 33-36 (Box 45)
      - International Biology Program, 1963-64 (Box 46)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950-1965 (Box 46)
    - National Science Foundation, 1950-1984 (Box 46)
      Brazil
    - National Science Foundation (Panel on Earth Science), 1953-56 (Box 46)
    - National Science Foundation Proposals, 1953-1970 (Box 46-47)
      - Axelrod, Daniel I., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Bavel, Cornelius H.M. van, 1953 (Box 46)
      - Brindley, G.W., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Bucher, Walter H., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Carder, Dean S., n.d. (Box 46)
      - Clemens, William A., Jr., 1966 (Box 46)
      - Cosgriff, John W., 1969 (Box 46)
      - Dickson, Frank Wilson, 1953 (Box 46)
      - Doolittle, Russell F., 1965, 1970; 2 folders (Box 46)
        - Folder 1, 1965 (Box 46)
        - Folder 2, 1970 (Box 46)
      - Dyson, James L., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Elvery, C.T. and Little, C. Gordon, ca. 1953 (Box 46)
      - Elvey, C.T., ca. 1953 (Box 46)
      - Ericson, David B., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Fox, Steven K., Jr., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Fryxell, Fritiof M., 1963 (Box 46)
      - Groot, John J., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Haas, Otto H., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Hall, E. Raymond, 1966-1974; 3 items (Box 46)
      - Harvill, Richard A., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Hipple, J.A. and M.L. Keith, ca. 1954 (Box 46)
      - Holzer, R.E., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Hopson, James A., 1967-1968 (Box 46)
      - Horner, B. Elizabeth and Taylor, J. Mary, 1963-1966 (Box 46)
      - Hull, David L., 1970 (Box 46)
      - Hussain, S. Taseer, 1974 (Box 46)
      - Jacobsen, Lynn, n.d. (Box 46)
      - Jenks, William F., n.d. (Box 46)
      - Jerison, Harry J., 1968 (Box 46)
      - Kaizer, Hans E., 1967 (Box 46)
      - Kennedy, George C., 1953 (Box 46)
      - Kerr, Paul F., n.d. (Box 46)
      - Kulp, J. Laurence, 1953 (Box 46)
      - Lehmann, Elvoy P., 1953 (Box 47)
      - Manier, Edward, 1968 (Box 47)
      - McCaleb, Stanley B., 1953 (Box 47)
      - McLean, James D., Jr., n.d. (Box 47)
      - Morgan, Robert W., 1971 (Box 47)
      - Newell, Norman Dennis (Box 47)
      - Olson, Everett C., 1955 (Box 47)
      - Parsons, Willard H., 1953 (Box 47)
      - Roach, Franklin E., 1953 (Box 47)
      - Roy, Rustum, n.d. (Box 47)
      - Sanford, John T., ca. 1954 (Box 47)
      - Shotwell, J. Arnold, 1954-55 (Box 47)
      - Simons, E.L., 1967 (Box 47)
      - Sokal, Robert R., 1965 (Box 47)
      - Stauffer, R.C., 1961 (Box 47)
      - Thom, W.T., Jr., 1953 (Box 47)
      - Turner, Francis J., 1953 (Box 47)
      - Tuttle, O.F., et al., n.d. (Box 47)
      - Van Valen, Leigh, 1968 (Box 47)
      - Wetzel, Ralph M., 1955 (Box 47)
      - Wolfe, Peter, 1953 (Box 47)
      - Yen, John Teng-chein, n.d. (Box 47)
    - National Science Foundation (refereed comments-grant proposals), 1951-71 (Box 47)
      ABC's by PI
    - National Science Teachers Association, 1962 (Box 47)
    - National Speleological Society, 1950-1951 (Box 47)
    - National Trust of Australia, 1975 (Box 47)
    - Natural History (magazine), 1929-42, 45-47, 50, 53, 56-60, 64-65, 75 (Box 47)
    - Natural History Press, 1967 (Box 47)
    - Natural Law Forum, 1960 (Box 47)
    - Natural Science Book CLub, 1971-72 (Box 47)
    - Nature (journal), 1955, 60, 70 (Box 47)
    - Naurich, W.P., 1970 (Box 47)
    - Nectario Maria, Hermano, 1938-39, 47 (Box 47)
    - Needham, Rodney, 1976 (Box 47)
    - Needles, Robert J., 1955 (Box 47)
    - Neeson, Frederick E., 1964 (Box 47)
    - Neff, Frederick C., 1954 (Box 47)
    - Neighbor, J.B., 1968 (Box 47)
    - Nelson, Clarence D., 1933 (Box 47)
    - Nelson, Elmer R., Jr., 1937-1941 (Box 47)
      Milwaukee Public Museum
    - Nelson, Gareth, 1972-76, 79 (Box 47)
      Systematic Zoology, fights re: systematics, Hennig
    - Nelson, N.C., 1933-41 (Box 47)
    - Nelson-National, 1965 (Box 47)
    - Ness, A.R., 1961 (Box 47)
    - Netting, M. Graham, 1940, 47 (Box 47)
    - Neuser, Katharina, 1984 (Box 47)
    - Neve, Michael, 1981 (Box 47)
    - Neville, Russell Trall, 1942 (Box 47)
    - Nevo, Eviatar, 1966, 80, 82 (Box 47)
    - New England Regional Primate Research Center, 1966 (Box 47)
    - New Hampshire, University of, 1963 (Box 47)
    - New Jersey College for Women, 1950-51 (Box 47)
    - New Mexico, University of, 1950, 53-54, 67, 69, 76 (Box 47)
    - New Rochelle, College of, 1962 (Box 47)
    - New School for Social Research, the, 1958 (Box 47)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1929, 37-40, 43, 46-48, 60, 62, 76, 82 (Box 47)
    - New York Association of Teachers of Biological Sciences, 1952-53 (Box 48)
    - New York Herald Tribune (newspaper), 1953, 55-56 (Box 48)
    - New York Public Library, 1950 (Box 48)
    - New York Review of Books, 1964, 67, 69 (Box 48)
    - New York Times (newspaper), 1940, 65 (Box 48)
    - New York Times Book Review, 1968 (Box 48)
    - New York University, 1934, 57 (Box 48)
      outline, syllabus for courses
    - New Yorker (magazine), 1971 (Box 48)
    - New Zealand Antartic Society, 1973, 78-79, 81-82 (Box 48)
    - Newberry Library, 1935 (Box 48)
    - Newcomb College, 1964 (Box 48)
    - Newell, Norman Dennis, 1947-49, 54 57, 60-61, 63, 65-66, 71-73, 79-81 (Box 48)
    - Newfield, Nancy, 1976 (Box 48)
    - Newman, James R., 1963 (Box 48)
    - Newman, Philip L., 1972 (Box 48)
    - Newsweek (magazine), 1947, 1951 (Box 48)
    - Nichols, Charles, 1959 (Box 48)
    - Nichols, G.S., 1928 (Box 48)
    - Nichols, Herbert B., 1941 (Box 48)
    - Nichols, John T., 1936 (Box 48)
    - Nichols, Rachel Alice Husband (Husband-Nichols), 1944, 46, 48, 78-84 (Box 48)
      Also under Husband, Rachel Alice
    - Nichols, Walter, 1959 (Box 48)
      Voice of America
    - Nicholson, Thomas D., 1970-71, 74, 77, 84 (Box 48)
      AMNH, Director
    - Nicol, David, 1940 (Box 48)
    - Niel, Andre, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Nielsen, Karl, 1957 (Box 48)
    - Nielson, Paul E., 1938 (Box 48)
    - Niklanovic, Michael D., 1972 (Box 48)
    - Nitzsche, George E., 1951 (Box 48)
    - Nixon, A. Allen, 1942 (Box 48)
    - Nlikovsky, Jiri, 1981 (Box 48)
    - Noble, Elmer R., 1959 (Box 48)
    - Noble, G.K., 1937 (Box 48)
    - Noble, Robert D., 1960 (Box 48)
    - Nogar, Raymond J., 1963, 66 (Box 48)
    - Nolan, Thomas B., 1950, 65, 78 (Box 48)
    - Nopesa, Franz Baron, 1929-30 (Box 48)
    - Norenheim, Carl J., 1972, 79 (Box 48)
    - Norling, Richard L., 1965 (Box 48)
    - Norman, H.B., 1940 (Box 48)
    - Norris, Kenneth S., 1947, 58, 67 (Box 48)
    - North Arizona, Museum of, 1948, 78 (Box 48)
    - Northern Arizona Society of Science and Art, Inc., 1958 (Box 48)
    - Northrop, Stuart A., 1949, 69 (Box 48)
    - Northwestern University (Harris Lecture), 1957-59 (Box 48)
      Abstract
    - Norton, Ruth W., 1955, 64 (Box 48)
    - Norton, W.W., and Co., Inc., 1947, 51 (Box 48)
    - Nova Pacifica Publishing Co., Ltd., 1981 (Box 48)
    - Novas, Fernando E., 1977, 81 (Box 48)
    - Novikoff, Alex B., 1943 (Box 48)
    - Nyessen, D.J.H., 1942 (Box 48)
    - O'Brien, Donald E., 1971 (Box 48)
    - O'Connor, Don, 1962 (Box 48)
      UPI
    - O'Gara, W.T., 1940 (Box 48)
    - O'Kane, W.C., 1941 (Box 48)
    - O'Leary, Nancy B., 1966-69 (Box 48)
    - O'Leary, Timothy J., 1965, 69, 78 (Box 48)
    - Oakes, Wayne, 1984 (Box 48)
    - Oakley, Kenneth, 1951 (Box 48)
    - Oakley, Margaret L., 1975 (Box 48)
    - Oberson, Viola L., 1963-64 (Box 48)
      Oregon Museum of Science and Technology
    - O'Brien, Donald E., 1971 (Box 48)
    - O'Connor, Don, 1962 (Box 48)
    - O'Gara, W.T., 1940 (Box 48)
    - O'Kane, W.C., 1941 (Box 48)
    - O'Leary, Nancy B., 1966-69 (Box 48)
    - O'Leary, Timothy J., 1965, 69, 78 (Box 48)
    - Oakes, Wayne, 1984 (Box 48)
    - Oakley, Kenneth, 1951 (Box 48)
    - Oakley, Margaret L., 1975 (Box 48)
    - Oberson, Viola L., 1963-64 (Box 48)
    - Obler, Arch, 1956 (Box 48)
    - Obrtel, R., 1971 (Box 48)
    - Odegard, Holton P., 1971 (Box 48)
    - Odishaw, Hugh, 1975, 79 (Box 48)
    - Odland, Dick, 1960 (Box 48)
    - Oehser, Paul H., 1936-37 (Box 48)
    - Oeser, O.A., 1968 (Box 48)
    - Oetteking, Bruno, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Oettingen, Katharina Neuser-von, 1984 (Box 48)
      Spekrum der Wissenschoft: Fossils, german
    - Ohio State Museum, 1954 (Box 48)
    - Ohio State University, 1959 (Box 48)
    - Ohio State University (Bownocker Lectures), 1945-1946 (Box 48)
    - Ohlman, Arthur, 1939 (Box 48)
    - Ohmart, Robert D., 1970-71 (Box 48)
    - Ohshima, Kwanshiro, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Oklahoma, University of, 1953-54 (Box 48)
    - Oklahoma, University of (Press), 1970, 72 (Box 48)
    - Oldt, Esther, 1969 (Box 48)
    - Oldt, Thomas, 1973 (Box 48)
    - Olic, Frank, 1941 (Box 48)
    - Olins, Donald, 1957 (Box 48)
    - Oliver, Adriana, 1928 (Box 48)
    - Oliver, James A., 1948, 65, 70 (Box 48)
    - Oliver, Mary Anna Hunter, 1938 (Box 48)
    - Oliver, W.R.B., 1947 (Box 48)
    - Olkin, Ingram, 1979 (Box 48)
    - Olsen, Edward J., 1981 (Box 49)
    - Olsen, Stanley J., 1956-1982; 2 folders (Box 49)
      American Philosophical Society; Paleontology; Publication -- American Journal of Science; Referee's report; Research support; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zoology
    - Olson, Everett C., 1937-47, 49, 54, 58, 61, 62, 65, 71-79 (Box 49)
    - Olson, Jane, 1968 (Box 49)
    - Olson, P.J., 1940 (Box 49)
    - Olson, Stanley, 1955 (Box 49)
    - Olson, Storrs L., 1973-75, 81, 84 (Box 49)
    - Olson, Todd R., 1970 (Box 49)
    - Olszewski, Charles T.R., 1958 (Box 49)
    - Omaha Bee-News, 1934 (Box 49)
    - Omenn, Gilbert S., 1972 (Box 49)
      Selection
    - Oppenheimer, Dave M., 1958 (Box 49)
    - Opton, Edward, 1950 (Box 49)
    - Orange Coast College, 1957 (Box 49)
    - Orbach, Ruth, 1970-71 (Box 49)
    - Orchard, Philip, 1983-84 (Box 49)
      New Zealand Antartic Society
    - Ordish, George, 1940-41, 51, 54-55, 57-58, 62, 79, 81-84 (Box 49)
    - Oregon, University of, 1951, 66, 69 (Box 49)
    - Oregon, University of (Condon Lecture), 1952-54, 59 (Box 49)
    - Orel, V., 1966 (Box 49)
    - Orientalia, Inc., 1973 (Box 49)
    - Orlov, J.A., 1934-35, 37, 46, 57 (Box 49)
    - Ornduff, Robert, 1968 (Box 49)
    - Orr, Gilbert M., 1948 (Box 49)
    - Orries a Ibars, Jose C., 1975 (Box 49)
    - Ortega, Enrique, 1967 (Box 49)
    - Ortega, Virgilio, 1972 (Box 49)
    - Orthung, Jane R., 1960 (Box 49)
    - Ortiz, Felix Aguilar, 1977 (Box 49)
    - Ortner, Donald J., 1976 (Box 49)
    - Orzack, Steven, 1980-81 (Box 49)
    - Osborn, A. Perry, 1941-42, 47 (Box 49)
      Human Destiny
    - Osborn, Chase S., 1933 (Box 49)
    - Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1925-1935; 2 folders (Box 49)
      American Museum of Natural History; Fellowships, assistantships; ongratulations, greetings, thanks -- Osborn, Henry Fairfield. 70th birthday; Paleontology; Photographs; Publication; Research support; Travel -- England; Travel -- South America; Zoology
    - Osborne, Richard H., 1960 (Box 49)
    - Osgood, Wilfred H., 1934-35, 39, 42, 47 (Box 49)
      Standing Committee on Nomenclaturer, AmSocMammal
    - Osmond, D., 1976 (Box 49)
    - Osmundsen, Lita, 1974 (Box 49)
    - Ostermeyer, Ed, 1979 (Box 49)
      Natural History Museum of Los Angles County
    - Ostrom, John H., 1964, 67-76, 78-79, 82-84 (Box 49)
    - Ottofy, Louis, 1937 (Box 49)
    - Outes, Felix, n.d. (Box 49)
    - Outhwaite, Leonard, 1938 (Box 49)
    - Owen, Tom, 1977 (Box 49)
    - Owens, Alun John, 1980 (Box 49)
    - Oxford University, 1950 (Box 50)
    - Oxford University Press, 1949-62, 69, 71, 73 (Box 50)
      Horses
    - Paaver, K., 1977 (Box 50)
    - Pacific Indemnity Company, 1940 (Box 50)
    - Pacific Mutual Life Insurance Company of California, 1926, 35 (Box 50)
    - Pacific Science Conference, 1940 (Box 50)
    - Padoa, Emanuela, 1972 (Box 50)
    - Page, Howard E., 1958 (Box 50)
    - Page, John, 1981 (Box 50)
    - Paillard, Inc., 1968 (Box 50)
    - Painter, John H., 1975-77 (Box 50)
      W.H. Freeman
    - Painter, Reginald H., 1943 (Box 50)
    - Palaeontological Society of India, 1953 (Box 50)
    - Palaeovertebrata (journal), 1982 (Box 50)
    - Palaontologisches Institut, 1959 (Box 50)
    - Paleobiology (journal), n.d. (Box 50)
    - Paleontological Institute (U.S.S.R. Academy of Sciences), 1962, 77, 84 (Box 50)
    - Paleontological Society, 1926, 35, 43, 45, 49, 52, 54-56, 68 (Box 50)
    - Paleontological Society (Joint Comm. on Zoological Nomenclature for Paleontology in America), 1945-48 (Box 50)
    - Paleontological Society of Washington (D.C.), 1940 (Box 50)
    - Paleontologieheskii Institut, 1981 (Box 50)
    - Paleontology Club (Yale University), 1925-26 (Box 50)
    - Palmer, C.M., Jr., 1968 (Box 50)
      Armadillos
    - Palmer, Harold S., 1937, 58 (Box 50)
    - Palmer, R.R., 1968 (Box 50)
    - Palmer, Ralph S., 1947-48 (Box 50)
    - Palmer, T.S., 1930-31, 33, 40, 42 (Box 50)
    - Palomino Horse Breeders of America, 1948 (Box 50)
    - Pandey, Kamla Kent, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Pangborn, Edgar, 1954 (Box 50)
    - Pangburn, Robert, 1975 (Box 50)
    - Panteleev, P.A., 1973 (Box 50)
      Int'l Theriological Congress
    - Panuska, Joseph Allan, 1960 (Box 50)
    - Paquin, V.M., 1958 (Box 50)
    - Paradise of the Pacific (magazine), 1945 (Box 50)
    - Paraguay, La Industrial, 1931 (Box 50)
    - Parcher, Stephen R., 1973 (Box 50)
    - Pardy, R.L., 1973-74 (Box 50)
    - Paris, University of (Sorbonne), 1965-66 (Box 50)
    - Paris, Virginia A., 1982 (Box 50)
    - Park, David, 1975 (Box 50)
    - Park, Madeline, 1959 (Box 50)
    - Park, Thomas, 1940, 42 (Box 50)
      Ecology
    - Parks, Charles, 1937 (Box 50)
    - Parks, W.A., 1935 (Box 50)
    - Parnall, Edward, 1964 (Box 50)
    - Parodiz, J.J., 1969 (Box 50)
    - Parpart, Arthur K., 1959 (Box 50)
    - Parr, A.E., 1946, 50-51, 57-59 (Box 50)
    - Parr, LaVone, 1971 (Box 50)
    - Parrington, F.R. (Rex), 1946, 65, 67, 69, 74 (Box 50)
    - Pascual, Rosendo, 1957-1984; 2 folders (Box 50)
      Biographical and personal data; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Paleontology; Patterson, Bryan; Photographs; Publication; Research support; Travel -- South America; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zoology; Zoology -- Nomenclature
    - Pasteur, Georges, 1961-65, 69 (Box 50)
    - Patte, Etienne, 1937 (Box 50)
    - Patterson, Bryan (Pat), 1931-1983; 5 folders (Box 51)
      American Museum of Natural History; American Philosophical Society; Biographical and personal data; Conferences and symposia; Evolution -- Teeth; Field Museum of Natural History; Harvard University -- Museum of Comparative Zoology; Leakey, Louis Seymour Bazett; Paleontology; Photographs; Publication; Recommendations; Requests for reprints; Society for the Study of Evolution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; Travel -- South America; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; Zoology; Zoology -- Classification; Zoology -- Nomenclature
    - Patterson, Colin, 1983 (Box 51)
    - Patterson, David K., 1978 (Box 51)
    - Patterson, John W., 1980 (Box 51)
    - Patterson, Lorraine, 1962 (Box 51)
    - Patterson, Neil (Mrs.), 1983 (Box 51)
    - Pauling, Linus and Ava Helen, 1957, 61 (Box 51)
    - Pauw, Karel de, 1976 (Box 51)
    - Pavan, Crodovaldo, 1982 (Box 51)
    - Pavlow, M.W., 1926, 33 (Box 51)
    - Payne, Melvin, 1963 (Box 51)
    - Paynter, Raymond A., Jr., 1982 (Box 51)
    - Peabody Museum of Archeology and Ethnology, 1941 (Box 51)
    - Peabody, Frank E., 1953, 56 (Box 51)
    - Peacox, Earle, 1937 (Box 51)
    - Pearl, Aaron, 1962 (Box 51)
      Loch Ness Monster
    - Pearl, Raymond, 1933-1940; 23.0 Item(s) (Box 51)
      Quarterly Review of Biology
      Editorial matters; Paleontology; Publication -- Quarterly Review of Biology; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Zoology
    - Pearlman, William H., 1958 (Box 51)
    - Pearse, A.S., 1940, 1950 (Box 51)
    - Pearson, Helga S., 1926 (Box 51)
    - Pearson, Oliver P., 1968 (Box 51)
    - Pearson, Paul G., 1978 (Box 51)
      American Institute for Biological Sciences Award
    - Pearson, Ronald, 1966 (Box 51)
    - Pease, Murray, 1949 (Box 51)
    - Peck, Joseph H., Jr., 1974 (Box 51)
      J of Paleontology
    - Peck, Robert F., 1979 (Box 51)
    - Peck, W.H., 1936-40 (Box 51)
    - Pecsi, Tibor, 1966-67 (Box 51)
    - Pedroja, Mary J., 1925, 32 (Box 51)
      Lydia's mother
    - Peers, Robert, 1929 (Box 51)
    - Peet, Creighton, 1928, 46, 50, 60, 62, 70, 72-74 (Box 51)
    - Pemberton, J.R., 1939 (Box 51)
    - Pena, Horacio Oscar, 1984 (Box 51)
    - Penn-Sheraton Hotel, 1959 (Box 51)
    - Pennak, Robert W., 1969 (Box 51)
    - Penner, Lawrence R., 1968 (Box 51)
    - Pennsylvania State University, 1958-59, 65, 75 (Box 51)
    - Percheron Horse Association of America, 1948 (Box 51)
    - Percy, Lord Eustance, 1952 (Box 51)
    - Perea, Luis, 1936-37 (Box 51)
    - Pergamon Press, 1979-80 (Box 51)
      Why and How
    - Perkins, James R., 1982 (Box 51)
    - Perkins, W. Harvey, 1964 (Box 51)
    - Perlasco, Carlos A.H., 1958, 60-61 (Box 51)
    - Perone, F.J., 1964 (Box 51)
    - Perry, Edmund, 1960 (Box 51)
    - Perry, H. Mitchell, Jr., 1969 (Box 51)
    - Person, Philip, 1959 (Box 51)
    - Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, 1964-65, 67 (Box 51)
    - Perspectives in Humanism, 1967 (Box 51)
    - Persuitte, David, 1967 (Box 51)
    - Peters, James A., 1971 (Box 51)
    - Peterson, Barbara and Roger, 1972 (Box 51)
    - Peterson, Lester H., 1974 (Box 51)
    - Peterson, O.A., 1926, 28, 32 (Box 51)
    - Petrica, Jerome B., n.d. (Box 51)
    - Petrunkevich, Alexander, 1949 (Box 51)
    - Petry, Loren C., 1956 (Box 51)
    - Pettingill, Olin Sewall, Jr., 1976 (Box 51)
    - Peyer, Bernhard, 1950-51 (Box 51)
    - Peyer, Hildegard, 1951 (Box 51)
    - Pfeiffer, John, 1959, 66-67, 72 (Box 52)
    - Pfizenmayer, E.W., 1926 (Box 52)
    - Phelps, William H., Jr, 1938-42, 45-46, 49, 64-68, 72, 78, 82 (Box 52)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Association, 1943, 50 (Box 52)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Book Awards, 1963-64 (Box 52)
    - Philip, C.B., 1941 (Box 52)
    - Phillips, Burr W., 1948 (Box 52)
    - Phillips, Marilynn, 1971 (Box 52)
    - Phillips, Wendell (Box 52)
    - Philomathean Society of the University of Pennsylvania, 1963 (Box 52)
    - Phleger, Fred B., Jr, 1940-42, 47 (Box 52)
    - Physical Science News, 1966 (Box 52)
    - Pianka, Eric R., 1962, 64, 77 (Box 52)
    - Piatrutgriey, A., 1936 (Box 52)
    - Piaz, Giambattista dal, 1963 (Box 52)
    - Pick, J.M., 1981 (Box 52)
    - Pickersgill, Barbara, 1976 (Box 52)
    - Piedmont University Center of North Carolina, 1967 (Box 52)
    - Piedras, Claudio Antonio, 1963 (Box 52)
    - Piel, Gerard, 1978, 80 (Box 52)
      Scientific American Library
    - Pierce, W. Dwight, 1933 (Box 52)
    - Pietzner, Carlo, 1967 (Box 52)
    - Pilbeam, David, 1966 (Box 52)
    - Pilgrim, Greg, 1930 (Box 52)
    - Pilgrim, R., 1947-48 (Box 52)
    - Pinari, S.P., 1973 (Box 52)
    - Pindar, George N., 1927-28, 33 (Box 52)
    - Pine, Ronald H., 1979 (Box 52)
    - Pines, Kapai, 1967 (Box 52)
    - Pinkerton, W.M., 1970 (Box 52)
    - Pinto Horse Society, 1948 (Box 52)
    - Pinto, Iraja Damiani, 1981 (Box 52)
    - Pires, Fernando Dias de Avila, 1961, 68 (Box 52)
    - Pirlot, Paul L., 1951, 69 (Box 52)
    - Pirone, Frank J., 1941 (Box 52)
    - Piscitelli, Joseph, 1967 (Box 52)
    - Piszek, Edward J., 1973 (Box 52)
    - Pittendrigh, Colin, 1953-65, 68, 73 (Box 52)
    - Pittsburgh Neuropsychiatric Society, 1966 (Box 52)
    - Pittsburgh, University of, 1958-62 (Box 52)
    - Piveteau, Jean, 1947-48, 59-60, 65 (Box 52)
    - Plane, Michael D., 1963, 76, 78, 82 (Box 52)
    - Plaster Jacket (newsletter for Florida State Museum), 1976 (Box 52)
    - Platnick, Norman I., 1980 (Box 52)
    - Platt, Raye R., 1936 (Box 52)
    - Pledge, Neville, 1969, 71 (Box 52)
    - Plenum Publishing Co., 1980 (Box 52)
    - Plowman, C.G., 1972 (Box 52)
    - Pocket Books, 1984 (Box 52)
      Simon and Schuster, Inc.
    - Pocock, Gerald, 1976 (Box 52)
    - Podrazik, Miriam, 1980 (Box 52)
    - Poe, Debbie, 1973-74 (Box 52)
      Computer Devices and Terminal General
    - Pofcher, Schlussel, and Katcher, 1955 (Box 52)
    - Poglayen, Ivo, 1961 (Box 52)
    - Poindexter, Patricia, 1964 (Box 52)
    - Politis, Nicolaos, 1969 (Box 52)
    - Pollitzer, William S., 1970-72 (Box 52)
      Am J Phys Anthrop
    - Polowsky, Joseph, 1972 (Box 52)
    - Pomerat, C.M., 1964 (Box 52)
    - Pomeroy, Carolyn, 1959 (Box 52)
    - Pomona College, 1954 (Box 52)
    - Ponnamperuma, Cyril, 1976 (Box 52)
    - Ponton, Gerald M., 1929, 32, 34, 58 (Box 52)
    - Pope, Betty, 1964 (Box 52)